DANIAL ABU BAKAR

Segar Road #01-372 | +65 9856 0243

<u>Danialabubakar91@gmail.com</u>

https://github.com/danialabubakar91

IT Analyst transitioning into a role in backend web development. I have 2 years of experience in VPMS development for insurance products with 6 months experience in Java with Springboot to build a restful web service. I also have 8 months of experience in an application support role, using SQL for investigation purposes. Currently working on personal projects to showcase some of the skills I have learnt from online bootcamp courses in web development.

TECHNICAL PROFILE

Languages:

• Python, JavaScript, Java, SQL, HTML, CSS

Databases:

- SQL Server Studio
- SQLite
- MongoDB
- DynamoDB

Version Control:

GitHub

TECHNICAL PORTFOLIO

GitHub:

https://github.com/danialabubakar91

Portfolio:

https://danialportfolio.herokuapp.com/

Tools:

- Visual Studio Code, Eclipse
- Microsoft Office Suite

Backend Frameworks:

- Django, Django Rest Framework
- NodeJS, ExpressJS
- Springboot

Frontend Frameworks:

Bootstrap

EXPERIENCE

1 JAN 2022 - PRESENT

UNEMPLOYED

- Enrolled in online web development courses
- Worked on portfolio site showcasing some of the projects I have worked on. Portfolio Site: https://danialportfolio.herokuapp.com/
- Worked on Python related projects with frameworks using Django and Django Rest Framework
- Worked on YelpCamp site while enrolled in Colt Steele's web developer bootcamp course

27 APR 2021 - 31 DEC 2021

SENIOR IT ANALYST, TRANSITLINK PTE LTD

- Supporting of TransitLink internal application systems.
- Troubleshooting of issues in Transitlink applications through SQL queries and log checking in servers
- Writing SQL scripts for data analysis and investigations for detecting issues caused by system or business operations
- Writing SQL scripts for data patching due to system or operational issues
- Coordinate with both business and IT side to resolve and enhance current application systems
- Conduct data extraction using SQL for Transcom investigations and Covid-19 contact tracing
- Supporting and coordinating of application deployment and verification activities

26 APRIL 2019 - 23 APRIL 2021

VPMS DEVELOPER, NTUC INCOME (CONTRACT UNDER AGILITY NEXUS)

- VPMS (Visual Product Modelling System) is a proprietary software used to calculate insurance premiums
- Worked on translating excel formulas used to calculate premiums from Excel spreadsheets, into VPMS
- Conduct testing to ensure correct premiums are calculated from VPMS
- Involved in Java development projects to build restful webservice using Springboot
- Other work scope involved working with business analysts to ascertain technical requirements from business requirements
- Collaborate with other IT teams on project development deliverables
- Adhere to project timelines from SIT, UAT and Production and to support incident tickets for issues raised in production.

5 FEB 2018 – 3 AUG 2018 MASTER DATA ANALYST, PROCTER & GAMBLE (CONTRACT UNDER KELLY SERVICES)

- Daily export of data from front end database system and backend database system.
- Produce daily scorecard reports using excel to identify gaps in data between front-end and back-end database systems.
- Using excel pivot tables and formulas such as VLOOKUP, index match, countif, and a variety of other formulas for data analysis to find root cause of data gaps.
- Support and coordinate with multi-functional teams to resolve issues found from data gaps.
- Incident monitoring and tracking of incident tickets and fulfilment requests to ensure issues from data gaps are resolved and requests are fulfilled.

EDUCATION

2015 – JANUARY 2018

BACHELOR OF BUSINESS INFORMATION SYSTEMS, UNIVERSITY OF WOLLONGONG

2009 - 2012

DIPLOMA IN COMPUTER ENGINEERING, SINGAPORE POLYTECHNIC